<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://warcraftpriests.github.io/bookofshadows/blog</id>
    <title>Book of Shadows Blog</title>
    <updated>2024-04-18T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
    <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://warcraftpriests.github.io/bookofshadows/blog"/>
    <subtitle>Book of Shadows Blog</subtitle>
    <icon>https://warcraftpriests.github.io/bookofshadows/img/book.jpg</icon>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Alpha Feedback - Voidweaver]]></title>
        <id>https://warcraftpriests.github.io/bookofshadows/blog/alpha-feedback-voidweaver</id>
        <link href="https://warcraftpriests.github.io/bookofshadows/blog/alpha-feedback-voidweaver"/>
        <updated>2024-04-18T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The following feedback is from the perspective of a Shadow Priest.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The following feedback is from the perspective of a Shadow Priest.</p>
<p>You can find all current bugs for Priests in The War Within <a href="https://github.com/SimCMinMax/WoW-BugTracker/issues?q=is%3Aopen+is%3Aissue+label%3A%222-The+War+Within%22+label%3APriest" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">here</a>.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="any-bugs-blocking-testing">Any bugs blocking testing?<a href="https://warcraftpriests.github.io/bookofshadows/blog/alpha-feedback-voidweaver#any-bugs-blocking-testing" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Any bugs blocking testing?" title="Direct link to Any bugs blocking testing?">​</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Voidwraith<!-- -->
<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/SimCMinMax/WoW-BugTracker/issues/1174" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Does not work with Mindbender</a> (see below section)</li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/SimCMinMax/WoW-BugTracker/issues/1175" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Does not trigger Idol of Y'Shaarj</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/SimCMinMax/WoW-BugTracker/issues/1179" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Sometimes melee's instead of casting</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/SimCMinMax/WoW-BugTracker/issues/1180" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Is not scaling with any of our Priest modifiers</a>. This includes Twist of Fate, Mastery, Shadowform, Idol of Y'Shaarj, Voidheart, etc</li>
<li>Currently <em>does</em> work with Inescapable Torment, unsure which half of this is intended, but guessing it is supposed to work with our talents.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Depth of Shadows<!-- -->
<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/SimCMinMax/WoW-BugTracker/issues/1172" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Proccing this puts Mindbender or Shadowfiend on cooldown</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/SimCMinMax/WoW-BugTracker/issues/1173" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Does not trigger Idol of Y'Shaarj</a></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/SimCMinMax/WoW-BugTracker/issues/1176" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Devour Matter 300% increase is not applying</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/SimCMinMax/WoW-BugTracker/issues/1178" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">After talenting into and out of No Escape, it is still active.</a></li>
</ul>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="hero-talents-that-create-frustrating-or-unsatisfying-gameplay">Hero Talents that Create Frustrating or Unsatisfying gameplay<a href="https://warcraftpriests.github.io/bookofshadows/blog/alpha-feedback-voidweaver#hero-talents-that-create-frustrating-or-unsatisfying-gameplay" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Hero Talents that Create Frustrating or Unsatisfying gameplay" title="Direct link to Hero Talents that Create Frustrating or Unsatisfying gameplay">​</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Current Entropic Rift window feels very busy and borderline overwhelming and you are rushing to try and get Void Blasts and Devouring Plagues out and do not have room to do much else. This is directly linked to feeling like we cannot quite "cap" the rift size or extension consistently. If that was fixed this might also be better to play with. There is some charm in having to chase the rotation here.<!-- -->
<ul>
<li>Currently Shadow also feels like it has to ramp to get meaningful damage out of the talent, the Void Torrent channel into then spawning the rift and then reaching peak 15 seconds later is a very long time in environments when things do not live that long.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Darkening Horizon feels very unachievable to get the full extension without Bloodlust, Power Infusion, and a lot of baseline haste while also getting lucky with procs. Not being able to max this except in rare cases is unsatisfying.<!-- -->
<ul>
<li>Reducing the cooldown of Void Blast, making it Instant Cast, working with other spells as well, and/or increasing how much extension you get per Void Blast would help</li>
<li>Changing it to a spammable spell like Discipline probably would not feel fun, as it would really hurt the value of non-filler spells during this window</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Collapsing Void Devouring Plague expansion feels extremely underwhelming or even non-existent, even after casting 5 Devouring Plagues the size of the rift is still smaller than 8 yards, which is less than Shadow Crash and by then it fizzles away.<!-- -->
<ul>
<li>Make it work with Devouring Plague ticks and/or significantly increase how much it is increased by per cast</li>
<li>Fantasy element and visually this is extremely underwhelming</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>When a mob dies that was the original target of Entropic Rift, this can feel super unsatisfying, especially if it remains as a small size since it currently does not move or re-target.<!-- -->
<ul>
<li>Would be awesome if an enemy dies in the rift it also expands and "consumes" them</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Entropic Rift not pulling enemies in feels unsatisfying. For a spell that closely resembles a black hole, I wish it acted more like it. The slow from No Escape is in a similar space but not nearly what I expected. In PvE the applications for the slow are quite underwhelming.</li>
<li>The choice node between No Escape and Dark Energy is unsatisfying. At the current size of the rift No Escape feels extremely underwhelming and likely will not have many use cases in PvE at the current size Shadow can get it to. In the current state it feels like Dark Energy will be preferred always.<!-- -->
<ul>
<li>Would love to see additions or changes to No Escape such as the black hole design mentioned above.</li>
<li>Adjusting the pacing/sizing that Shadow can get the rift to would certainly help No Escape.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>The choice node between Devour Matter and Void Empowerment does not feel satisfying. Devour Matter is an extremely niche ability in almost all types of content, where it will only provide a small amount of value even if the condition is met. On the other hand Void Empowerment is always useful and consistent and provides value every 30 seconds with Malediction.<!-- -->
<ul>
<li>If we had this choice node on live, in current examples where we do face enemies with shields (Tindral, Fyrakk, Iridikron) that is such a small portion of the fight, Void Empowerment would still be the better choice.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Currently locks you into the bottom right side of our spec talent tree for this spec as Void Torrent, Malediction, and Idol of C'Thun all have such strong synergies. Could be frustrating when taking any Shadow Word: Death points in Voidweaver that also encourage spending points in the bottom left side of our spec tree.</li>
<li>In certain cases Shadow might be incentivized to cancel Void Torrent early just to get the rift to spawn sooner. This might just come down to tuning of Void Torrent though. Spawning at the start of the cast would have even more problems depending on tuning of Void Torrent, end is better but that incentive is still there. This is also contributing to having a somewhat length burst/ramp time for our damage. Will take 3 seconds of Void Torrent + up to 15 seconds of the Rift before it collapses, which is a long time for damage especially in environments like Normal dungeons.</li>
</ul>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="hero-talents-where-functionality-is-confusing-unclear-or-difficult-to-track">Hero Talents where Functionality is Confusing, Unclear, or Difficult to Track<a href="https://warcraftpriests.github.io/bookofshadows/blog/alpha-feedback-voidweaver#hero-talents-where-functionality-is-confusing-unclear-or-difficult-to-track" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Hero Talents where Functionality is Confusing, Unclear, or Difficult to Track" title="Direct link to Hero Talents where Functionality is Confusing, Unclear, or Difficult to Track">​</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Cooldown of Voidwraith is confusing since when taking Mindbender the cooldown is not lowered at all and remains fixed at 2 minutes, making Mindbender a completely dead talent.</li>
<li>Depth of Shadows (<code>451308</code>) has an internal cooldown of 1 second. This can be confusing for players because at higher haste levels and a Death and Madness reset you can cast Shadow Word: Death back to back and the second cast would be unable to proc the effect.</li>
<li>Proc rate of Depth of Shadows and the health threshold is currently unknown and not shown on the spell.</li>
<li>Inner Quietus <a href="https://github.com/SimCMinMax/WoW-BugTracker/issues/1177" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">does not increase the direct damage of Shadow Word: Pain</a>. This is particular is confusing with Catharsis.</li>
<li>Voidwraith's talent tooltip indicates that it deals "up to 50% additional damage, dealing more damage to higher health enemies" but the actual spell deals a flat 135% of spellpower and then if the mob is above 50% health it deals 100% increased damage. This is inconsistent with the talent tooltip and not sure what is intended.</li>
<li>There is nothing baseline in-game to track how many times you have extended Entropic Rift (and if you have any left) with Darkening Horizon without using some kind of WeakAura. (x/5)</li>
<li>There is nothing baseline in-game to track how many times you have expanded Entropic Rift with Collapsing Void without using some kind of WeakAura. (x/8)</li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/SimCMinMax/WoW-BugTracker/issues/1185" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Void Blast's tooltip shows a low number for Shadow</a></li>
<li>Visual of Entropic Rift can be hard to see in certain environments on the ground, and because it does not re-target after the original dies this is important to know where to drag mobs into, especially for your Tank in PvE environments. The rift not re-targeting after the original dies is also unintuitive.</li>
</ul>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Publik</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/seanpeters86</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="alpha" term="alpha"/>
        <category label="voidweaver" term="voidweaver"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Welcome]]></title>
        <id>https://warcraftpriests.github.io/bookofshadows/blog/welcome</id>
        <link href="https://warcraftpriests.github.io/bookofshadows/blog/welcome"/>
        <updated>2024-01-12T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Welcome to Book of Shadows!]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Welcome to Book of Shadows!</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Publik</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/seanpeters86</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="news" term="news"/>
    </entry>
</feed>